JACOB PARKER

SKILLS

React and React Native developer, with tonnes experience, including commercial products. Contributor to React Native, familiar with Swift, Objective C, and some Java on Android

JavaScript

Specialist in JAVASCRIPT, both in browser and with NODEJS. Favourite libraries and tools are LODASH (FP), REACT and REACT NATIVE, REDUX, RXJS, D3, ESLINT, WEBPACK, BABEL, GULP, JEST, and FLOW. Author of many REACT, REACT NATIVE and CSS packages on NPM. Have previous experience with ANGULAR.

CSS Skilled in vanilla CSS, to SASS, and POSTCSS setup. Also experienced with Java-Script solutions, including CSS MODULES, and am a collaborator on STYLED COMPONENTS. Experience in responsive design, BOOTSTRAP, FOUNDATION, BEM, and progressive enhancement.

Python

Knowledgable of PYTHON, with experience in web frameworks, including FLASK, and data analysis libraries NUMPY and SCIPY. Contributed to PYGMENTS syntax highlighting project, used by O'Reily for their book publishing.

PROJECTS

GITHUB VIEWABLE AT HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/JACOBP100.

APP STORE



RECORA a natural language calculator. Built using a custom parsing engine and React Native. A web client is also available. *iOS* | *GitHub*



SCILINE a scientific calculator using latex to display and edit equations. Made using native Objective C and Swift.



POCKETJAM to help musicians shift the pitch and adjust the tempo of songs for practising. Built with React Native, and Swift for the playback code. iOS

BLOG POSTS

- → You Aren't Using Redux Middleware Enough
- >> You Aren't Using Redux with Observables Enough

EXPERIENCE

ZOOPLA, TOWER BRIDGE

2018

Full stack development on the new stack for the property search pages. Set the team up for React (Preact) components, including rendering both on the client and server, and internationalisation.

OUR STAR CLUB, FITZROVIA

2018

Architected React web and React Native applications for a sports-based social media platform. Set up key infrastructure and guided the team through native development. Implemented many native code libraries in both Swift and Java where existing React Native bindings were not available.

CONCENTRA, ST PAUL'S

2017-2018

Senior developer working on a web application specialising in visualising large organisational hierarchies with over 500,000 people, and making it fully interactive at 60fps. Used D3, React, Redux, among other libraries.

AUTOTRIP, MONUMENT

2016-2017

In charge of architecture and UI/UX design of a fully responsive, progressive web app for drivers to view car journeys recorded with the company's GPS device. Built using React and Leaflet JS.

Other Places

Tido Music (2015–2016) *Geneity* (2014–2015)

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF YORK

2011-2014

First Class honours BSc in Theoretical Physics.